<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Missing Data Solutions</title>
    <link>https://missingdatasolutions.rbind.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Missing Data Solutions</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://missingdatasolutions.rbind.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Missing Data News</title>
      <link>https://missingdatasolutions.rbind.io/news/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://missingdatasolutions.rbind.io/news/</guid>
      <description>On this page you will find news about missing data and applied biostatistical methods, referrals to other interesting blogs or articles.
Calibration beltWith package givitiR a calibration belt can beplotted to assess the calibration of dichotomous outcome models. This is assumed a better procedure compared to theshortcomings of the Hosmer and Lemeshow test, that may become significant in large datasets, although predicted andobserved probabilities agree well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shiny apps</title>
      <link>https://missingdatasolutions.rbind.io/shiny/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://missingdatasolutions.rbind.io/shiny/</guid>
      <description>On this page you will find interactive learning tools of missing data methods
Simple Imputation methodsThis app shows the effect of applying single imputation methods in the case of one outcome variable and one covariate with missing data.Go to the app
Multiple ImputationThis app shows how imputed values are calculated during each iteration and imputation step according to the Multivariate Imputation by Chained Equations (MICE) algorithm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>the R psfmi package</title>
      <link>https://missingdatasolutions.rbind.io/psfmi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://missingdatasolutions.rbind.io/psfmi/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionOn this page you will find information about the psfmi package.The package contains functions to pool logistic (psfmi_lr), Coxregression (psfmi_coxr) and linear and logistic mixed models (psfmi_mm)in multiply imputed datasets. It is also possible to apply backward variableselection in multiple imputed datasets (Be aware that backward selectionmay result in overfitted and optimistic prediction models, see TRIPOD). Backward selection should therefore be followed by internal validation of the model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to Missing Data Solutions</title>
      <link>https://missingdatasolutions.rbind.io/2020/07/welcome-to-missing-data-solutions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://missingdatasolutions.rbind.io/2020/07/welcome-to-missing-data-solutions/</guid>
      <description>Most examples and solutions will be concentrated on Missing Data topics. Posts may also concern Regression modeling, Clinical Prediction models and Spline regression modeling. Most examples originate from FAQs asked during statistical consultations or during courses.
Examples are provided for applied researchers and frequenly in RStudio.
RStudio is an open source free package with a lot of possibilities,making it easy to share code so that you can use the code exampleand adjust it to your own needs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multiple Imputation and Cross-validation</title>
      <link>https://missingdatasolutions.rbind.io/2020/02/mi-cross-validation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://missingdatasolutions.rbind.io/2020/02/mi-cross-validation/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionThis page contains information of three methods that are implementedin the psfmi package and that combine Multiple Imputation with Cross-validation for the validation of logistic prediction models. Currently the methods are only available via downloading thepsfmi package via Github. Do this:
install.packages(“devtools”)
library(devtools)
devtools::install_github(“mwheymans/psfmi”)
library(psfmi)
The cross-validation methods are adjustments of the methods described in thepaper of Mertens BJ and Miles A.
The methods are implemented in the function psfmi_perform and are called:cv_MI, cv_MI_RR and MI_cv_naive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Model Stability analysis after Multiple Imputation</title>
      <link>https://missingdatasolutions.rbind.io/2020/01/model-stability-analysis-after-multiple-imputation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://missingdatasolutions.rbind.io/2020/01/model-stability-analysis-after-multiple-imputation/</guid>
      <description>Model Stability analysisTo build a prediction model you can reliably use backward selection in a data situation wherethere are enough persons that are positive and negative on the outcome compared to the numberof potential predictors when you combine it with internal validation and model stability analysis.
You can find more about model stability analysis in the papers of Royston and Sauerbrei, Sauerbrei and Schumacher, Heymans et al.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>psfmi package update</title>
      <link>https://missingdatasolutions.rbind.io/2020/01/psfmi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://missingdatasolutions.rbind.io/2020/01/psfmi/</guid>
      <description>With the psfmi_mm function pooling and selection of (generalized) linear mixed models, i.e linear and logistic mixed models, is possible. With the psfmi_stab function the stability of models after using psfmi_lr, psfmi_coxr and psfmi_mm can be evaluated. The latter function uses (single) bootstrapping for the psfmi_lr and psfmi_coxr functions and cluster bootstrapping for the psfmi_mm function. With the function the bootstrap inclusion frequency of predictors and models can be estimated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Package psfmi</title>
      <link>https://missingdatasolutions.rbind.io/2019/05/psfmi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://missingdatasolutions.rbind.io/2019/05/psfmi/</guid>
      <description>More information about the package can be found on the Cran website.
You can easily install the package by running install.packages(&#34;psfmi&#34;) in the Console window in Rstudio or R. The development version can be installed from Github by using:install.packages(&#34;devtools&#34;)
library(devtools)
devtools::install_github(&#34;mwheymans/psfmi&#34;)
library(psfmi)
If you have questions about the psfmi package send an email to mw.heymans@amsterdamumc.nl or leave a message below. Enjoy using the package!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Applied Missing Data analysis Book</title>
      <link>https://missingdatasolutions.rbind.io/2019/01/bookmi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://missingdatasolutions.rbind.io/2019/01/bookmi/</guid>
      <description>The book can be found here.I have written that book with my colleague Iris Eekhout.It is a first draft and it will be continuously updated and improved. For comments and suggestions leave a comment below or email me at: mw.heymans@vumc.nl. Thank you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Backward Logistic Regression after MI - forcing variables in model</title>
      <link>https://missingdatasolutions.rbind.io/2019/01/psfmi-lr-forcing-variables/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://missingdatasolutions.rbind.io/2019/01/psfmi-lr-forcing-variables/</guid>
      <description>Forcing predictors in the model can be applied by using the keep.predictors option inthe psfmi_lr function. These variables can be continuous, dichotomous orcategorical variables. Also more than one variable can be forced in the modelduring backward selection. Examples will be given below.
ExamplesPooling with BS and forcing dichotomous variable in the modelPooling with BS and forcing categorical variable in the modelPooling with BS and forcing dichotomous and categorical variable in the modelPooling with BS and forcing dichotomous variable in the modelPooling Logistic regression models over 5 imputed datasets with backward selectionusing a p-value of 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Logistic Regression after Multiple Imputation - different selection criteria</title>
      <link>https://missingdatasolutions.rbind.io/2019/01/backward-logistic-regression-after-multiple-imputation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://missingdatasolutions.rbind.io/2019/01/backward-logistic-regression-after-multiple-imputation/</guid>
      <description>The different methods are described in the papers of Marshall et al and Eekhout, vd Wiel and Heymans.
Be aware that backward selection may result in overfitted and optimistic prediction models, see TRIPOD. Backward selection should therefore be followed by internal validation of the model.
ExamplesPooling without BW and method D1Pooling with BW and method D3Logistic RegressionPooling without BW and method D1library(psfmi)pool_lr &amp;lt;- psfmi_lr(data=lbpmilr, nimp=5, impvar=&amp;quot;Impnr&amp;quot;, Outcome=&amp;quot;Chronic&amp;quot;,predictors=c(&amp;quot;Gender&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Smoking&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Function&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;JobControl&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;JobDemands&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;SocialSupport&amp;quot;), method=&amp;quot;D1&amp;quot;)pool_lr$RR_model## $`Step 1 - no variables removed -`## term estimate std.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Steps to externally validate a prediction model</title>
      <link>https://missingdatasolutions.rbind.io/2019/01/steps-to-externally-validate-a-prediction-model/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://missingdatasolutions.rbind.io/2019/01/steps-to-externally-validate-a-prediction-model/</guid>
      <description>Original prediction modelWe will externally validate the following prediction model:
library(foreign)dat.orig &amp;lt;- read.spss(file=&amp;quot;Hipstudy.sav&amp;quot;, to.data.frame=T)## re-encoding from UTF-8library(rms)dd &amp;lt;- datadist(dat.orig)options(datadist=&amp;#39;dd&amp;#39;)dat.orig$Mobility &amp;lt;- factor(dat.orig$Mobility)fit.orig &amp;lt;- lrm(Mortality ~ Gender + Mobility + Age + ASA, x = T, y = T, data = dat.orig) fit.orig## Logistic Regression Model## ## lrm(formula = Mortality ~ Gender + Mobility + Age + ASA, data = dat.orig, ## x = T, y = T)## ## Model Likelihood Discrimination Rank Discrim.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Missing Data Guideline</title>
      <link>https://missingdatasolutions.rbind.io/2018/12/missing-data-guideline/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://missingdatasolutions.rbind.io/2018/12/missing-data-guideline/</guid>
      <description>The Missing Data guideline can be found here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://missingdatasolutions.rbind.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://missingdatasolutions.rbind.io/about/</guid>
      <description>My name is Martijn Heymans. I am an Assistant Professor of Applied Biostatisticsand Missing Data Methods at the department of Epidemiology and Biostatisticsof the Amsterdam University Medical Center (Amsterdam UMC), The Netherlands.
My work consists of statistical consultancy, supervising PhD projectson methodological and clinical topics and lecturing courses inepidemiology and biostatistics for the bachelor and Master’s Programmein Epidemiology epidm.nl and Medicine.
I like to work with RStudio and try to provide solutions for applied clinicalresearchers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Martijn Heymans</title>
      <link>https://missingdatasolutions.rbind.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://missingdatasolutions.rbind.io/contact/</guid>
      <description>Interested in my work?
mw.heymans@amsterdamumc.nl
Martijn51</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modern Missing Data and Multiple Imputation Methods</title>
      <link>https://missingdatasolutions.rbind.io/missingdata/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://missingdatasolutions.rbind.io/missingdata/</guid>
      <description>On this page you will find information about modern Missing Data Methods.
Regression modelsI have written an R package that is called psfmi, whichmeans “Predictor Selection Functions in Multiply Imputed Datasets”
Missing Data websitesYou may visit the Website of Iris Eekhout,who wrote her PhD on missing data in questionaire data. She compared missingdata methods for questionnaire missing items and total scores.I supervised that project.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
